A Guide to the William James Rucker Autograph Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William James Rucker Autograph Collection 1812-1881
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-404
This collection consists of 16 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library from William James Rucker, September 7, 1933.
Scope and Content Information
Chiefly letters of prominent 19th century Virginians: John Randolph (1812); Andrew Jackson (1830); John Marshall (1831); Edwin Henry Landseer (1845); John C. Calhoun (1849); Edwin Henry Landseer (1851); Charles Dickens (1858); William Cabell Rives (1861); John Letcher (1862); Jefferson Davis (1864); J. E. B. Stuart (1864); Alexander H. H. Stuart (1866); John Letcher (1866); Gilbert C. Walker (1872); Joseph E. Johnston (1881); Fred W. M. Holliday (1881)
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- John Randolph to Micajah Woods 1812 June 5
- Andrew Jackson to Col. Francis Preston 1830 June 16
- John Marshall to his wife and son 1831 February 7
- Edwin Henry Landseer to Joseph Miller 1845 August 10
- John C. Calhoun to William Cabell Preston 1849 February 21
- Charles Dickens to Joseph Miller 1858 May 28
- William Cabell Rives to L. P. Walker 1861 July 14
- John Letcher to Micajah Woods 1862 December 24
- Jefferson Davis to Col. Lucius Bellinger Northrop 1864 January 4
- J.E.B. Stuart to Mrs. B.H. Shackelford 1864 January 27
- Alexander H. H. Stuart to Major Micajah Woods, and others 1866 February 18, with envelope
- John Letcher to Micajah Woods 1866 June 15
- Gilbert C. Walker to Micajah Woods 1872 May 8
- Joseph E. Johnston to Micajah Woods 1881 March 1
- Frederick William Mackey Holliday to Micajah Woods 1881 September 28